As a senior data scientist, I start my day with a daily stand-up to align priorities.
I take part in planning sessions.
In some cases, I lead task definition.
I also manage two team members, I support them, I give them feedback, and help them grow professionally.
I also attend leadership meetings to align OKRs, and often, I take the initiative by proposing or picking up new tasks when I spot opportunities.
Our team is technical and focused on building AI-powered products for the company’s chatbots.
I work with technologies like Python, Docker, GitLab, MongoDB, and JupyterLab.
My technical work focuses mainly on the backend of a conversational API powered by AI.
I maintain internal tools including a clustering app and another for prompt evaluation.
I also collaborate on the development of an experimental whatsapp bot that uses our API to test new features.
Its performance, as well as others’, is evaluated continuously by me.
Occasionally, I experiment with large language models to explore new features.